RG 004:131, Southington Probate Court
Connecticut State Library
Southington Probate Court records
1825-1973
Connecticut State Library
Connecticut. Probate Court (Southington District)
81.5 cubic feet
Record books, 1836-1973; Probate files, 1825-1987 (Decedent estates, 1825-1933; trustee accounts, 1901-1957; wills, 1888-1973, trusts, 1948-1973; incapables, 1941-1950; miscellaneous records, 1867-1987).
RG004_131
1922-002, 2007-073, 2011-096, 2012-022
Historical Note
Southington, Hartford County, Town established in October 1779, Parent Town: Farmington
The Southington Probate District was constituted May 24, 1825, from the Farmington Probate District. The Southington Probate District merged with the Cheshire Probate District to create the Cheshire - Southington Probate District which serves the municipalities of Cheshire and Southington.
Town of Southington, Probate District chronology:
October 1779 - May 23, 1825, Farmington District
May 1825 - January 4, 2011, Southington District
January 5, 2011 - Present, Cheshire - Southington District
For Probate Court contact information and hours of operation see,.
Scope and Content
Probate record books, volumes 1-79, 1836-1973. Contact the probate court to access original record books numbered after 79. See Alternative Form Available note below.
Probate files, 1825-1987 (Decedent estates, 1825-1933; trustee accounts, 1901-1957; wills, 1888-1973, trusts, 1948-1973; incapables, 1941-1950; miscellaneous records, 1867-1987). Probate files may consist of estates, conservatorships, guardianships, commitments, and insolvencies. See Alternative Form Available note below.
Inventory control book, 1825-1907 (coverage). Also known as the Godard Digest, it is a list of probate files transferred to the Connecticut State Library. It was compiled at the Connecticut State Library under the direction of State Librarian George S. Godard.
Arrangement
Record books in accessions 2011-096 and 2012-022 and are numnbered 1 to 32 and 33 to 79 respectively. There are two volumes numbered 15 and none numbered 16.
Probate files in accession 1922-002 are arranged alphabetically. Probate files in accession 2007-073 are arranged alphabetically within type of matter.
Other Finding Aid
Record Books: Index cards for the record books have been scanned. Ask History and Genealogy staff for assistance. See Alternate Form Available section for volumes available on microfilm.
Probate Files: The Probate Estate Papers Index, located in the index corridor adjacent to the History and Genealogy Reading Room, has two parts, a general index covering most of the state, and a Hartford Probate District index covering Hartford and some surrounding towns, 1820-1920. The index cards are arranged alphabetically by individual's last name and first names. The cards have the individual's name, town of residence, probate district, and list of items contained in the estate packet. To request retrieval of an estate packet, copy at least the estate name, file date, and probate district name from the index card. The probate files in Accession 1922-002 are represented in this index.
Probate Files: The History and Genealogy reference staff has access to an index for the probate files in accession 2007-073.
Index Terms
Subjects:
Probate records -- Connecticut -- Southington
Places:
Southington (Conn.)
Restrictions on Access
Researchers should first consult use copies when available. See Alternate Form Available Section below.
Accession 2011-076, Record books, 1836-1940; Accession 2012-022, Record books, 1918-1972; and Accession 2007-073, Probate files, 1867-1987, are stored at an off-site facility and therefore may not be available on a same-day basis.
Probate files dated 1921 or later are RESTRICTED pending review by State Archives staff as they may contain confidential documents. Tax returns (succession, transfer and estate tax returns and all attachments) from January 1, 1921 and later are confidential per Connecticut General Statutes §12-15. Adoptions (all documents) from January 1, 1944 and later are confidential per Connecticut General Statutes §45a-754. Removals of parent as guardian of minor (all documents) and terminations of parental rights (all documents) from October 1, 1975 and later are confidential per Connecticut General Statutes §45a-754. Contact State Archives staff for assistance. Adoptions (all documents) from January 1, 1944 and later are confidential per Connecticut General Statutes §45a-754. Contact State Archives staff for assistance.
See the policy.
Alternative Form Available
Record books, volumes 1-5, 7-8, 10-11, 14, 17, 19, 22, 23, 26, 28, 1834-1919; probate files, 1825-1880 (Accession 1922-002); and inventory control book (Godard Digest) were microfilmed by the Genealogical Society of Utah and are available for use in the History and Genealogy reading room or through the.
Provenance
The probate files in accession 1922-002 were transferred to the Connecticut State Library on November 6, 1922.
The probate files in accession 2007-073 were transferred to the Connecticut State Library on May 17, 2007.
The record books in accession 2011-096 were transferred to the Connecticut State Library on January 11, 2011.
The record books in accession 2012-022 were transferred to the Connecticut State Library on March 6, 2012.
Container List
- Record books, 1836-1940; 16.5 cubic feet (31 volumes); 2011-096
  - Wills and distributions, 1857-1873 (Volume 1)
  - Records, 1836-1843 (Volume 2)
  - Records, 1843-1851 (Volume 3)
  - Records, 1851-1877 (Volume 4)
  - Records, 1857-1865 (Volume 5)
  - Decrees, 1863-1872 (Volume 6)
    On spine: "Records"
  - Records, 1863-1869 (Volume 7)
    On spine: "Manuscript"
  - Records, 1869-1874 (Volume 8)
  - Decrees, 1872-1881 (Volume 9)
  - Decrees, 1874-1879 (Volume 10)
  - Decrees, 1879-1885 (Volume 11)
  - Orders and decrees, 1881-1887 (Volume 12)
  - Bonds, 1881-1898 (Volume 13)
  - Records, 1885-1890 (Volume 14)
  - Decrees, 1887-1893 (Volume 15)
  - Applications and returns, 1887-1905 (Volume 15)
  - Records, 1890-1895 (Volume 17)
  - Decrees, 1893-1899 (Volume 18)
  - Records, 1895-1900 (Volume 19)
  - Bonds, 1898-1918 (Volume 20)
  - Decrees, 1899-1904 (Volume 21)
  - Records, 1900-1903 (Volume 22)
  - Records, 1903-1907 (Volume 23)
  - Decrees, 1904-1907 (Volume 24)
  - Applications, 1905-1923 (Volume 25)
  - Records, 1907-1913 (Volume 26)
  - Decrees, 1909-1913 (Volume 27)
  - Records, 1913-1918 (Volume 28)
  - Decrees, 1914-1922 (Volume 29)
  - Decrees, 1917-1926 (Volume 30)
  - Bonds, 1918-1933 (Volume 31)
  - Applications and returns; Sales of real estate, 1918-1940 (Volume 32)
- Record books, 1918-1973; 28 cubic feet (48 volumes); 2012-022
  - Records, 1918-1922 (Volume 33)
  - Records, 1922-1926 (Volume 34)
    On spine: "Manusscript"
  - Applications, 1924-1939 (Volume 35)
  - Records, 1924-1931 (Volume 36)
  - Decrees, 1926-1932 (Volume 37)
  - Records, 1931-1936 (Volume 38)
  - Orders and decrees, 1929-1942 (Volume 39)
  - Bonds, 1935-1948 (Volume 40)
  - Records, 1936-1940 (Volume 41)
  - Applications, 1940-1950 (Volume 42)
  - Records, 1940-1944 (Volume 43)
  - Applications and returns; Sale of real estate, 1934-1950 (Volume 44)
  - Orders and decrees, 1942-1948 (Volume 45)
  - Records, 1944-1948 (Volume 46)
  - Records, 1948-1951 (Volume 47)
  - Orders and decrees, 1948-1955 (Volume 48)
  - Bonds, 1948-1959 (Volume 49)
  - Applications, 1950-1958 (Volume 50)
  - Applications and returns; Sale of real estate, 1951-1962 (Volume 51)
  - Records, 1951-1954 (Volume 52)
  - Records, 1954-1957 (Volume 53)
  - Orders and decrees, 1955-1962 (Volume 54)
  - Records, 1957-1960 (Volume 55)
  - Applications, 1958-1964 (Volume 56)
  - Bonds, 1960-1970 (Volume 57)
  - Records, 1960-1962 (Volume 58)
  - Orders and decrees, 1962-1966 (Volume 59)
  - Applications and returns; Sale of real estate, 1962-1968 (Volume 60)
  - Records, 1962-1964 (Volume 61)
  - Records, 1963-1964 (Volume 62)
  - Applications, 1964-1970 (Volume 63)
  - Records, 1964-1965 (Volume 64)
  - Records, 1965-1966 (Volume 65)
  - Bonds, 1966-1972 (Volume 66)
  - Records, 1966-1967 (Volume 67)
  - Records, 1967-1968 (Volume 68)
  - Records, 1967-1968 (Volume 69)
  - Records, 1968-1969 (Volume 70)
  - Bonds, undated (Volume 71)
    This volume is unused and contains blank forms only.
  - Applications, 1969-1972 (Volume 72)
  - Applicatins and returns; Sale of real estate, 1969-1971 (Volume 73)
  - Records, 1969 (Volume 74)
  - Records, 1969-1970 (Volume 75)
  - Records, 1970-1971 (Volume 76)
  - Records, 1971 (Volume 77)
  - Records, 1971-1972 (Volume 78)
  - Records, 1972-1973 (Volume 79)
- Probate files, 1825-1907; 18.5 cubic feet; 1922-002
  - Abell - Beman (Drawer 1)
  - Bemiss - De Neefe (Drawer 2)
  - Derby - Hitchcock, L. (Drawer 3)
  - Hitchcock, M. - Moore (Drawer 4)
  - Moran - Sloper, A. (Drawer 5)
  - Derby - Z. (Drawer 6)
- Inventory Control Book, 1825-1907; T003073
  Index of the probate files in ccession 1922-002
  Also known as the Godard Digest
- Probate files, 1867-1937, bulk 1901-1933; 18.5 cubic feet; 2007-073
  - Decedent estates, 1867-1933, bulk 1901-1933
    - Adams - Bailey (Box 1)
    - Baker - Bissell (Box 2)
    - Blakeslee - Bradley (Box 3)
    - Brady - Campbell (Box 4)
    - Campfield - Clark (Box 5)
    - Coleman - Culliney (Box 6)
    - Culver - Dlugoo (Box 7)
    - Dolan - Dutton (Box 8)
    - Eder - Fogg (Box 9)
    - Folcik - Giles (Box 10)
    - Gill - Hanley (Box 11)
    - Hardsay - Hopko (Box 12)
    - Horisk - Johnson (Box 13)
    - Johnston - Keltonic (Box 14)
    - Kennedy - Larouka (Box 15)
    - Latimer - Lowrey (Box 16)
    - Ludecke - McNessa (Box 17)
    - McNulty - Morse (Box 18)
    - Moss - Nichols (Box 19)
    - Nickerson - Oxley (Box 20)
    - Paddock - Plumb (Box 21)
    - Plummer - Richards (Box 22)
    - Richter - Shanahan (Box 23)
    - Shanley - Stannard (Box 24)
    - Starkey - Triano (Box 25)
    - Trustel - Warner (Box 26)
    - Waselkewices - Willette (Box 27)
    - William - Woodruff (Box 28)
    - Woolworth - Zwick (Box 29)
  - Trustee accounts, 1901-1957
    - Levi D. Frost, 1901-1911 (Box 30)
    - Marcellus B. Wilcox, 1918-1957 (Box 30)
    - Andrew W. Cook, 1902-1907 (Box 30)
  - Wills, 1888-1973
    - Aldi - Zifcak (Box 31)
  - Trusts, 1948-1973
    - Andrus - Cushing (Box 32)
    - Daniels - Rubin (Box 33)
    - Salvatore - Yeamans (Box 34)
  - Incapables, 1941-1950
    - Adamowitz - Nettleton (Box 35)
    - Palmieri - Zygmunt (Box 36)
  - Miscellaneous records, 1867-1987